DEBDAS GHOSH

5540 Fifth Avenue, Apt 13, Pittsburgh, PA 15232, USA

Contact No: +1 (412) 320 0303 E-mail ID: deg107@pitt.edu / <u>89debdas@gmail.com</u>
Website: <u>www.debdasghosh.com</u>
LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ghoshdebdas/</u>

Highly analytical and process-oriented Data Analyst / Machine Learning Engineer with in-depth knowledge of Database, Statistics, Big Data capture, manipulation, Object Oriented Programming and Information Visualization. Furnished insights, analytics and business intelligence used to advance opportunity identification, process reengineering and corporate growth. Have excellent communication skills, expert in problem solving, innovative.

EDUCATION

- University of Pittsburgh, Master of Science in Information Science, 2019-2021 pursuing
- West Bengal University of Technology, Master of Business Administration (Systems), 2016-2018
- University of Calcutta, Bachelor of Science Computer Application, 2006-2009

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Recruitment and Admission Assistant, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, September 2019 – Present

• Responsible for maintaining a high level of customer service to applicants and prospective students, maintaining and updating customer relationship management (CRM) system information, organizing and assisting with recruitment events. Also helps to manage the student ambassador program.

Spencer's Retail ltd, Kolkata, April 2013 – August 2019 Manager - IT, July 2015-August 2019

- Conducted data mining, data modeling, statistical analysis, business intelligence gathering, forecasting, presentation and benchmarking. Data analytic supports decisions for high-priority, customer service improvement, stock fill rate approximation and process reengineering.
- Used quantitative data gathered to develop an understanding of customer behavior, demographics and buying patterns. SCM Analytics, sale predictions, Market research analytics.

Assistant Manager – IT, April 2013- June 2015

- Built APIs for exposing customer data (over 500 GB) to supports Analytics, CRM, e-business.
- Worked on time complexity, optimization, feature selection, data extraction, cleaning, algorithms.
- Managed and developed various web sites and portals like Employee incentive, Customer complaint management, customer relationship management (CRM), Property Management, and eWallet management
- Developed Mobile Apps for Retail Operations like Rider App, Picker App, Order Management App for e-commerce operation, Stock check app, HR portal App, Online Sales Dashboard App

Web Developer, Micronix Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Kolkata Branch, Oct 2010-April 2013

- US Patent granted on 09, Feb, 2016 (https://patents.google.com/patent/US20140098140). Objective was to present Spiral design search gallery.
- Developed and maintained various web and mobile projects for US/Canada based clients.
- Oversaw client calling and project management.

Web Developer, DrWebMedia, Kolkata, August 2009-Sept 2010

- Helmed the web division team and a 6-member creative team of this Startup company.
- Created web sites, intranet software, also done Unit Testing, Load Testing, Functional Testing.

ACADEMIC PROJECT

Title: Breast Cancer Classification by Machine Learning

Objective was to detect whether a lump is benign or malignant using DNN and CNN by Tensorflow. Duration of the project was 12 weeks, Team Size: 3, Individual Role: Python Coding, Sample collection, Testing.

Title: Bad Loan Detection

Objective was to analyze Lending Club data and make a prediction of Bad Loan occurrence. Duration of the project was 2 weeks, Team Size: 3, Individual Role: Python Coding, Sample collection, Testing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Expertise: Data Analytics, Data Science, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Deep

Learning, Neural Network, Human Information Processing, Algorithm Design, Natural Language Processing, Artificial Intelligence, DBMS, MIS,

Web & Mobile Apps Development

Software: MS Office, MS Project, Tableau, Qlikview

• Languages/Skills: Python, R, PHP, C, C++, MySql, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

• Technologies: GIT/SVN, REST, SOAP, LAMP, AWS, NumPy, SciPy, pandas, scikit-

learn, dplyr, ggplot2

CERTIFICATIONS:

Data Science and Machine Learning Certification, Ivy Professional School, Kolkata, 2017-2018

Advance Hardware and Networking, HCL Career Development center, Kolkata, 2009